Ladies and gentlemen please welcome such a della.
Good morning everyone and welcome to build twenty fifty.
It's exciting to be here at...san francisco.
In fact I was just recounting I've been and,
every...conference of ours since nineteen ninety one in fact the very first one as
a...developer and after that as an employee at microsoft
...just awesome to be here.
I know there is revel fantastic show lined up for you we have lots of things to talk about
in today's keynote...of the rest of the conference lots of things to show
you lots of announcements many new things but,
I think are going to be very exciting in terms of what you
will make of them in day one and what you will do on day two...thereafter?
For me in some sense this conference.
Is all?
About celebrating.
And, challenging.
The creativity...the in genuinely.
To build.
great things on top of platform innovations that we make available to you.
And, that.
Phenomenon is not new.
In fact it goes back to the very origin of our company.
Microsoft was founded by to developers.
Who had a bold ambition to empower other
developers to build new and great thanks?
In fact that tweet you see on the screen.
Is the tweet from paul allen on
...fortieth anniversary...forty in april?
And, these are the first lines of code.
...bill and paul wrote it turns out that bill rolled the run-time and paul
...everything else in this nice common about we should put better errors so,
it started in the very beginning.
When you look at it that?
Ethos.
Laws changed in the forty-year since.
Lot-of technologies of com lot-of technologies have gone in fact the very first
basic interpreter was written on a pee-pee ten with an eighty,
eighty emulator that was built so that you could target the al
tear micro computer.
And, in the forty years a lot of devices of common gone a lot of technologies of
...gone as they should.
...remain constant is that ethos.
That core than we are
...develop a company and a platform company first it is our mission
to empower every person an organization on the planet to
...and when we talk about empowering every person
it starts by empowering every developer on the planet?
What you want to hear us talk about in this conference and even...
morning's keynote is perhaps the broadest lens through which we
...developers development and platforms?
We're going to want developers from student developers to
...ops to enterprise developers to isv
...people writing mobile apps
...venturing into virtual reality in mixed reality
all of these developers to...exploit take advantage of
the platform innovation that you will see this morning and throughout this conference.
Want-to make sure that
we build bridges free we want you to be able to bring your
scales your technology choices your languages to
...platforms and then build from there new and great
thinks.
Concept of that approach.
Is something that's going to
be deeply ingrained in everything we do across all of our platforms?
Over the last year I've had a chance to talk to many developers.
Throughout the world.
I met a couple student developers...in developers who won the imagine
plop last year from australia labeled
...fantastic mobile app that it made it possible.
For-you to be able to detect.
Anemia in children by just using a simple
app and taking a...and that at now is changing lives in africa
and other developing parts of the world I had a chance to meet a middle school
in the wrong single who...to robots that could walk the stairs
and in our eyes I could see that was just the very beginning of what she's going to do.
I...a chance to meet some enterprise developers in germany working in an
...equipment manufacturer and
they will fundamentally changing transforming
the business to becoming a software company sas company.
So, I taught that it's perhaps appropriate.
To kickoff build.
By talking to one such developer.
In fact he's a musician.
Who had a dream and...calls himself
...accidental developer throughout...
To change.
How music is compose?
Please help me welcome david william...
Hi, david hi great senior great to be the thanks for coming
up it's like...do you tell us a little bit...your dream your
...so far absolutely so music notation is probably something that a
lot of you in this room haven't really thought about before but it really is the written language
of music it's almost like a coding language of music actually...it has some similarities
with code you can even write-in csharp or upshot...probably better for...very.
That's until now there's been to main ways you can really write music traditionally using
...paper which is very creative maybe not that
convenience sometimes all the digital way which is very laborious
to input but very convenient once it's in that form so I really wanted to make something where you
could take the creativity and convenience and smashing together and create this
...way of writing music amazing...want to show us what
you built absolutely subtler stuff that is handwriting recognition for media notation.
But, I've actually been working on a piece the last few weeks.
A piece of string quartet and piano.
As you can see I can use touch to interact with the
school you could a big school here this is note nursery rhyme.
And, let's go to the and we've got a couple of...left to do so I figured we could finish it up on stage and
...your...music illiterate but go aheadwell,
I don't...
okay let's just take the pen I'm going to start writing in the bars so it's very
natural the idea behind the app was if you could write...should be able to a?
If you can write music you should be able to know how to use the app you don't need to really learned too much
...very intuitive as...move into the next bar.
...notations recognized intended to
...innovation moi thank you moi.
But, actually this is actually interactive notation now so I can...dot.
And, maybe I should slur some of these to.
You think swimming's play like you drunk okay I'm getting so much trouble flap.
Using touch I can...bar...and just pull this out this is a great thing about surface
and windows was really the only platform that we could do this
for because it really understands the difference between my fingers and the pen and that
...that's really...making this into to the natural I'm just going to say this
...beat...that using the pena...
And,...in a string run here.
...that up and you can see that we've got a nice flash stringing up to the top
so let me just to one less thing double...copy this down.
That's cool.
So, let on that.
Okay, and, we can play this back.
What's the also...
What's...reaction I know that this has been out for a few months is it now
...just a few weeks...the...already been absolutely incredible breathtaking
really we've heard from people all over the world we have an eleven-year-old composer...writing
her second up for on the...first...second andninety one-year-old
...back in love with writing music again it's really been this students ...in the classroom
to classroom and it's really just an incredible reaction has been breathtaking awesome thank you so much
...the megawatt.
That's what's most striking about today's developers...all of you
which is one person or a small group of people with...dream
in a passion can have such huge impact.
By taking advantage of these platform technologies who would've thought that music
composition can be changed with touch in inc and that's what we live
for as a platform company we want to be able to take inspiration from the apps
you build drive platform innovation so today's keynote
is about three major platform transformations and
...we want to talk about first
are cloud platform.
We aspire to build.
An intelligent cloud back-end for the world's applications
running on all devices we want to have.
The capability to manage infrastructures spanning datacenters
so that means storage compute in the network that's not just about a datacenter as
a computer but all of the datacenters coming together in support of these intelligent
applications we want to have rich applications services input
...services such as machine learning and
democratize the access to those capabilities so
that every developer on every platform can build intelligent apps.
Second we want to talk about office as a platform.
We want to move far beyond individual applications
in their api to building are rich.
...of data as a platform.
We want you to be able to consume that graph extend that
graph.
And, we'll talk a lot about that.
We want to talk about windows.
Windows ten.
Represents a new generation of windows built.
For an era of more personal computing from rats very
to the holographic computer where the mobility of the
experience is what matters not the mobility of the device.
...kick things off let
me have scott got three come up instance stage and talk about cloud platform thank you very much.
Thank you...everyone and welcome to built.
...you just talk about our three core envisions as a company
I'm now going to continue the conversation and talk about the work we're doing to build the
intelligent clout this is a broad ambition that spans a wide range of cloud services
at microsoft including office re sixty-five and dynamics.
Today I'm going to talk about the work we're doing to
our this ambition using as your.
Answer is microsoft's cloud computing platform enables you
to move faster and do more badgers hyper scale...platform in over the
last several years we've built out asher to run all over the world?
The circles on this map indicate agile regions which are made up of clusters of datacenters
where you can run deploy your...
Today we have nineteen unique as a...open for business
that's more locations and more countries...us and the google klout combined and this enables you to run
your applications closer your customers and employees than ever before and compete
and even more geographic markets.
We continue to invest billions of dollars each year building out new infrastructure
...cloud platform now managers more than one million servers.
This enables you to build apps without having to worry about your
...platforms capacity enables you to scale your solutions to any size.
...offers the choice and flexibility of a full spectrum clap.
Enables you to build apps that scale from personal projects
optic global scale applications you can start from scratch for new
...you can easily leverage your existing investments and skills.
Is open supports the ability to target multiple devices
use multiple operating systems programming languages...
Data services and tools...to put all of your app...or support hybrid deployments
that spanned on premises or other...
You can choose to use...just for infrastructure just use it for base compute storage
and networking you can also take advantage of a coherent set of highly engineered
services to build your apps even faster...cloud platform...tools combination
together deliver on match productivity enable you to move faster and be even more
successful for busy twelve months for the adder team since our last build conference a
year-ago we deliver more than five hundred new asher services and features
in that time...a greatly expanded the footprint in capabilities of
...delivers...what we're seeing is as...kind of expanded
our features as we've expanded our footprint around the world we're seeing the usage of asher continue to
rapidly-growing we...more than ninety thousand new
asher customer subscriptions now being created every month
...those customers are creating some really amazing applications more than one-point-four
million sequel databases are now being used by applications hosted inside out your
way more than fifty trillion objects now stored in the...system.
Four hundred twenty five million users
...directory system three million developers
...with...visual studio online services
...online suite of developer sas offerings we're seeing the growth and
xtraction badger happen not just in the enterprise and business user space but,
more than forty percent of...revenue and usage now comes actually from startups and from my
...behind these large momentum numbers arson truly amazing customer
...the slide contain some of...logos just a few of
...company's doing great things and asher and throughout today's keynote
...here me talk more about some of...specific stories and some of the reasons why...using a measure.
...things we know is that a cloud platform must offer the flexibility of choice
...enables you to use the best of...windows ecosystem and the best of
the linux ecosystem together as...enables easily reuse the skills
you already have regardless of the programming languages you use...take advantage
of both core infrastructure capabilities and higher-level platform services
and microsoft's unique and...the only hyper scale
...provider that architect's those higher-level services and program
model capabilities to run...multiple environment's including
...on premises datacenters that you already have as well as other clouds besides our own.
From the beginning of agile even braced open-source in a very deep way
...over this past year in particular we've taken a number of...steps
to use open-source even more broadly last year we announcer plans to deeply
embrace darker and darker ecosystem report asher in windows server and
may...a fundamental part of our application platform.
Will also open-source our core dot net runtime technology and announcer
plans supported on multiple platforms as...obviously make it first-class when running
within containers and this combination is really powerful enables even more developer flexibility
...choice?
We'd like to...things off is actually invite the...globe and markers
...which onstage here to talk about this work and show off pretty cool demo
...action here's bent.
Thank you scott.
So, for the view...not aware doctor has just celebrated its second birthday so, freely
were used to thinking of...kind of like a human two-year-old...stumbles occasionally
spits up and keeps those of us...closest to it up at night so, sort of surprising to be up here
on stage it build in fact I talk about the five big surprises that we've had in working with
microsoft at all or many relate to this notion of how we can take openness
and portability and flexibility and use it to empower developers now if you're not familiar with
...started two years ago by solomon hikes who felt that
developers fundamentally are spending far too much of their time.
Doing rework worrying about dependencies wearing about servers instead of just building awesome
apps and initial innovation was let's make it possible to take any application and
its dependencies package them up in the digital equivalent...shipping container
enable any application that stock rise to interact with any other...rise application
and run any server the last october when we went up to meet with microsoft
...proud of the fact...networking for linux you could take any
linux application...arise...and run it on any linux server and quite frankly we
saw we leaves redmond with an agreement to make
...for linux run well on hyper v or run well
...manager but then we have the first of those big five surprises and the first big surprise was that we
were not only...work on docket for linux we're going to work on doctor for windows so we're going to
enabled...four million...linux developers to join all the millions of
...windows developers and make it possible using standard darker using
open-source to take any windows application
...and run it on any server second-rate...that we had was this
is not only about code was also about content collaboration
...familiar with doctor, you know, we have a service called...hub that has about one hundred twenty thousand
...microsoft has not only
integrated darker hub into all of its developer platforms but is contributing actively to
doctor hub not just dockers windows components but all of these great new
opensource dot net for links components delivered again is doctor containers to the hub.
Third-grade surprised that we had was that microsoft embrace the notion of what you need to do to
make multi container apps work and embrace the notion if you want to make most container
apps truly portable you have to be open about how you do orchestration as well so
were so thrilled that microsoft has embrace dockers open orchestration initiatives compose machine
...warm fourth-grade surprising yes,
there's more ...those three things you're not only going to be able to
make great multi container windows applications a great multi container
windows applications you'll be able to mix and match windows containers
...containers which means you'll be able to use a linux back-end
...windows front-end or vice versa basically choose the best damn tools for the best
...application that you want to build and run it on any server.
And, the...and perhaps...surprise we've had working with microsoft
...is happen quickly and everything that I've spoken about is either live or working well in the
lab right now so without further ado I'd like to bring a...innovate...of asher onboard
to show you what happens when you combine these great platforms together again empower developers.
Think that.
Mark I love the...thank you great search
...everybody right so what I've got right in front of you here is an
...dot net five application fabric...and e-commerce site kind of a standard
...I'm going to be doing some dev test on the first thing I'd like to do is to deploy it to
a doctor container running in a windows server machine on this step test box I've got a virtual
machine running windows server with...support
darker container support and I'm going to take a look at the containers that I've already got running in
that virtual machine...executing the darker ps command which
lists the active containers you can see...got to containers active one is a
mein crafts server and the other one is no, js application which shows that
...containers on windows support many different run times and languages that you might be using.
Now what I'm going to do is package up the fabric cam applications that I can also deployed
into container and I'm going to use a several doctor commands here one called
doctor build which will package it up...tag the
image that's produced with the name fabric cams so it's easy to remember.
And, then go ahead and package that...going to be executing a series of steps which take that
asp dot net five application package it up in a
...revised image the next step.
Is to run that container with that image
...type darker run dash it to make
it interactive you'll see why I'm doing this in a second and?
Forget the documents darker.
Run and fabric cam.
Now the reason that I've had it be interactive so that we can print-out the ip address so
I can see the ip address of the website that's going to launch that fabric
...if I go back and do a darker ps at this point
you'll see that fabric came image has been launched into a container here...one of the
really fun parts about using the
...client is that if you don't specify name for your container it comes up with
a random one so let's go see what names...come up with it called this one tender
...on look at that but that's what are the odds of that coming up like that?
So, let's take a look
at website now which is going to be active launch ieee.
The ip addresses ten fifty dot
...twenty two and we're hitting tend...fifty.
Dot one-zero...and there we go dot net running in
windows server container executed with darker but I'm showing you a lot of technologies
...somebody might not be familiar with so just a quick raising and how many people have heard of linux?
Okay, for those people and they're watching a lot about a third of the audience...hands.
Just getting everybody raise their hand of course.
But, what I'm going to show you is...mention that we've got dot net support on linux and
we've integrated it with darker containers as well?
So, here I've got the same exact application
and this time I'm going to sh into a linux virtual machine and run the
doctor ps communicative got no containers running in that virtual machine instead of using
darker run to...right from visual studio using the publish command.
Right here I've configured it to launch to that darker host here's the ip
address that host when I type publish press publisher it's going to package it up
...execute the same darker...commands to deploy that fabric came application
on to linux if I go back and type doctor ps again you'll see
there's fabric can latest and there's the name prickly was
...always fun to look at the names.
Of the...energy creates.
Let's go see if that websites come up and sure enough there it is
and you can see that that's the same ip addresses...h command so I'm looking at the
darker container running on that virtual machine but now there's more I'm doing dev test of this
...application and I'd like to continue to use visual city of to do that and
I can now with integration of container debugging into visual studio somebody
got a server explore go-to virtual machines there's a doctor vm and there's the prickly
was...container I attach the butter.
just as a normal visual studio debugging experience I've got the libraries loaded here and you can
...sure enough there's the core clr
for linux underneath this application that I've...attached to.
...I want...break point here on the function that
I'm debugging I go back to the website
it refresh and I'm at the break point debugging.
Dot net in linux deployed in the doctor content...
So, we've been developing
across platform version of dot net core one-time in the open on get
...the last several months and excited today the announcer also releasing now
preview addition of the runtime in pre-compressor file binary format that you
can download in start using for windows for linux as well as for...
That's...incredibly exciting time in the world today
disruption is changing economy in a fundamental way
are not just in technology but in traditional service industries as well
...would have predicted that both the taxi and the hospitality business
...turned upside down five years...innovative companies like remover...b and
b are doing just that every organization is looking for ways to engage customers
better empower their employees more and ultimately transform the value they
deliver and developers and the applications and solutions that they build
played absolutely integral role in enabling us in fact increasingly digital
laps and technology...businesses to...their customers
and differentiate from one another and it's never been a better time I think right now than to be to be a developer.
Badger enables you to...transformation
...make you and your teams even more successful with asher we deliver a rich set
...higher-level services that provide fully engineered solutions that enable you
to move faster in achieve more and the combination of our
cloud platform in tools really delivers unparalleled developer productivity as you do this your
three-m is a customer...I think provides an excellent example of what...productivity can really
...largest companies in the world eighty, eighty eight thousand employees and
lowly deliver tens of thousands of products and three-m is using as your to build the
back ends for many of these products now they love the agility that
asher provides them to move quickly in deliver even more value and what the initial projects
the hosted on manager was an internal mobile app that they wanted to
...their sales force to sell a new offering that
...just actually come out with and a small roman team that actually never used
...your before signed up on a friday...spent the weekend building the app and
had by the end...can had a fully production ready version deployed on measure
...their sales force on monday and this ability to quickly
create robust enterprise ready applications with super-fast development cycles
...provided three-m with incredible business agility and helps
move even faster as an overall organization...of the great productivity solutions
asher delivers is are asher app service this is a really powerful offering that
were released just last month and provides a...capabilities that...quickly build
...scale both web...mobile applications anywhere in the world?
...service allows you to write back encode logic using dot net java
no gs php and python.
Ityou can easily enable continuous integration workflows ...it from
online...source repository like visual studio online get hub in bit pocket and
that enables its so that every time a developer...encode into one of those services
...automatically building tested deploy to a private production slot
everything's looking good and basically turned on the production and
...for monitoring analytics on top of it.
Using...built-in all skill capability you can set of rules so once you
deploy the application your application...automatically scale-up based on incoming
traffic in fact you get a massive influx of traffic you can basically
...up a huge number of instances and handle basically any
amount load and when your traffic drops as you can basically automatically shut
down those resources to help you save money and pay only for what you actually need?
Google features we've added recently to the as
...enterprise connectivity...allows you the ability to set
up a virtual private networks that allows you to connect back to an on
premise enterprise network and axes apps and data that you wish to make available
...really easy to integrate with existing enterprise solutions you already have
address service also now provide support for easily integrating data
and functionality from popular sour solutions like
...sixty-five dynamics and sales
force and you can use the logic apps functionality within app service to
create long-running workflows to automate business processes.
...to do is invite...here...to show off...or as
...service and what you can build...
Hi, friends.
You know, we're really excited about the maker movement
and things like raspberry pies and three-d printers
...pick-up one of these are great and one of the applications that we brought here the fabric
...application is a...and they sell things like printer
...three-d printers and net we know why files and things like that but they also offers
...I can go and upload a three-d print I've got a
three-d object here and three-d builder that you can go and get up on the windows store
someone upload him into this application that is running in as
your app service...we bring him up and then hit upload
this modern application...you've got actually got a little javascript three js...showing me the
model that tell me where I can pick it up and when and this is now going to go through a process
it's talking to a back-end order service the one that we saw
and let's switch over into visual studio and see how we built that
now this is that asp dot net five application using the dot net course
...are a and using modern techniques that is talking to the back-end
this order details back-end is running within the context of asher and
we're using html five cs history all the kinds of modern things that you'd expect
...actually bringing in bauer and...inside
of visual studio and because I'm a web developer I want to use my
web development skills to make other applications so we also have
the back-end for the administrators so when someone at the store gets
that three-d print we can click on the order they've got access to that print so
they're using this application on a surface to talk to the same
order api that the website does we've got built into visual studio
...tools for apache cordova that are also using html and javascript and
we're reusing some of that javascript as well and I can go
and generate mobile applications I could certainly use cplus-plus or tools like
salmon in this case tools for patchy cordova have allowed me to create
a mobile app so I can go and make purchases from the store and also check on my
order you maybe have seen the windows emulator that runs on hyper v that comes
with visual studio but you may not be familiar with the android
...this is an android emulator that comes with visual studio you have this
and I can go and check on my order from that android emulator running under hyper
v at full speed all part of the apache cordova tools that are
built in here...also includes debugging and...really amazing experience for people making mobile
applications on any platform let's switch over to visual studio online and
see our managing this code now in this case our team is working on
it get repository that's running in visual studio online you can see john galloway is making
Changes here but not only are we doing source control within via so but
we're also managing...backlog so we can keep track of what's working and what's
not working in this con bon war we've got full support for work items but more interestingly
to me is that workflow that the team is going through we've got the
...running in visual studio online as well so this asp
net five dot net course you are application is building in
via and then deploying out to the applications in as your
app service automatically now if I switch over to
badger I can see...application in the api host
here and when I move that into production
...within...itself and see the deployments here as well so I can see
it deployment that john put out on sunday click on that
and that integration with visual studio online I can see his commits
...that build succeeded so I check into get visual studio
online it runs the build runs the tasks make sure that everything is okay sends
it out into asher once it's in as your in production I can also scale
...can automatically scale it coming here
and scale by I can set the number of instances and a target range of the
...of the cpu goes above a certain amount of the application will scale so I
get the full lifecycle from visual studio all up through
production and now this application in production scaling I
want to get insights into what's going on you would expect to have great web insights
we've got application insight showing is all sorts of details we have dependency
tracking all the way down to a single line of code so from visual studio and as
you've got the best dev ops that allow teams to create both web and mobile
apps with our recent integration of hockey app I've got the same deep
insights for mobile applications so inside integrated into asher you can see
here the mobile app crashes events sessions by country I can go
all the way down to a single line of code and here's actually the ios version
of this application and I can go and see specifically what worked what didn't down to
inexact line in this case of swift code such as three hundred sixty
degree view of any platform from the highest level all the way
down to the lowest-level to a single line of code so this is a lot to take
...let's step back for a second get an understanding about how this fits
...we've got web apps we've got mobile applications
those are talking to api in the back-end when I submitted my order
it went to this order api written...sp net five-and-a-quarter clr?
Those api apps can be written by me or they can be written by third-party or brought in
from our marketplace but...really interesting thing is this concept of logic
applications because there's business processes like when that order gets completed I want to get
notified as a customer about that so let's take a look at what a logic application.
Let me switch over here we go so this is an application here where
we've got individual api apps the sequel connector is going
to be looking at the data for the orders and then it flows through this
workflow from one api up to another using a technology called swagger
where that metadata is going to the system into sales force and then in this case
we're posting a message to
slack I can bring in that order api that we created
in sp net and then get the details for that order you see that
actually got populated using that swagger details and
then it knows about previous things within this workflow
is a reliable durable workflow in the cloud and now I can click on truly
...and bringing that truly a connector and then send a message to let
me know when this when this order is completed.
So, here I can access any aspects of
...flowing through the system in this case outlook at the
phone-number and we will have the from number
...number.
And, then under text here we're going to have.
...person sales force first name your order is
reading this is the kind of common business process that you don't necessarily want to
...code because it changes a lot and this is all happening in the cloud
...this business orchestration
service called logic apps and you can integrate this with any
existing application running on any language not just dot net node python anything that create
...that can...swagger application can do this now.
I think this is pretty amazing but I feel like perhaps I haven't sufficiently
blow your mind and I promised a number of people that I would do that so let's take a moment and then
switch over to our.
Mcintosh share now on this
...you can see that I can load up visual studio online I can manage my code and
...my cross platform dot net applications I can do that using any one of
the many editors that one would use amac
like e-max sublime and things like that but inevitably I find myself going into spotlight on
...and just wishing that there was a member of the visual studio family that I can somehow run.
I'm really, really happy to announce that visual studio code.
This is a code optimized development tool that runs natively on windows
...analytics it supports dozens of languages out-of-the-box
...great.
Application for all kinds of things that you're going to do that are
code focused but it's not just a simple editor it has deep
insight into what's going on this is the same fabric ham order details application here
...code...I can see the references
are go and go into order details.
From here I can hover over individual objects
get information about them and help and I get real
intel us sense not just auto complete in this case powered by the
open-source tools of roslyn and omni...
So, this is pretty freaking amazing I can also.
Do things like this will bring in a little refactoring here
make a change say this and I've got get?
And, gifts and I can push it visual studio online...where
will then run through the process be built tested deployed and scaled to
asher which is pretty fantastic visual studio code but,
this is still not really blowing my mind I feel I could do
even better so why don't we take a moment and switch over to google into.
now I'm in my application in this case I'm using a mono application big
thanks to the folks at mono help to help us with mono four-point-one that this
demos running on I can now click on debug.
Launch an interactive debugging session so now I'm on a
...in a dot net app doing a debug session I've got
local variables I've got a call stack I've got break points all in this great
lightweight code editor visual studio code this I think
makes the point that visual studio is now if family of tools for
every developer and asher is the cloud back-end for
everyone up and I just got a text message on
my band that my three-d print is being delivered how nice thank you
I now those that's great now my scott you action figure as a...a
...scott those kind of agree example the type of end-to-end productivity the
combination of as your are visual studio family now provides...
as howard mentioned earlier three sixty-degree view from coding to deployment to testing to
source control management to running and scaling your application it does at all you also
...saw...news addition to the visual studio family which is visual studio
...visual seo code is a code optimize editing environment
...small fast and provides both coding...sense and
debugging support as you saw is for integration forget and one of things were
...on windows on...as well as...development machines and
really excited announced the remaking available for free.
And, even better...pleased to announce later
today the first download of it will be made available on all those platforms for you start using.
Our mission with visual studio is to provide best in class tools for every
developer and we now have tools for developers who like lightweight code optimize
elders as well as for those looking for a full development enterprise id.
And, with visual studio online is
...showed we now provide a full suite of developer services that run in the
cloud that delivery full application lifecycle management experience
including source control plug-in work item tracking continuous integration builds
...testing performance crash analytics a whole bunch more what
...you can take advantage of all these services directly from any of our visual studio development tools
where you can also use them from any other development tool as well ...
this really enables you to build amazing applications in this mobile first
cloud first-world ever really excited to talk more about this in the
breakout talks and all the great features that are coming in visual studio this year.
The mortgage
recent roller famous article few years ago we talk about how software is eating the world
...how companies will increasingly deliver value through online
services today more than ninety percent of all technology companies
are now delivering or building online sas services to deliver more about value
and better connect with our customers and many of our biggest customers using
...today are using it to build and deliver sas services to their
customers this includes both born in the cloud companies as well as enterprises
that are reinventing themselves by becoming technology firms.
Acura whether is a great example of one of those companies
...largest weather forecasting services in the world
the originally actually eight of us customer and switched asher to our whether service
they process more than six billion data requests each day through the
rate gis for temperature and weather forecasts and
they use asher for weather prediction as well as the our all of their ios android
windows out documents another great example they provide electronic signature signing
sat service of a growing at three hundred-percent europe or year for seven years now
...now service more than one hundred twenty thousand enterprise customers
are fantastic example of a successful startup
...is network billions.
...healthcare is working
...provide their customers were doctors and hospitals easier ways to collect
analyzed and report healthcare data...deployed multiple sas applications on
...or meeting the most stringent regulatory environments this week
...build we're going to talk about a number of new technologies that we're delivering a
...you to build great high scale sas services like these
one of the technologies...talk about is something we call badger service fabric
...fabric is the high control distributed computing framework we
...our own high skill cloud services and
we battle hardened it over the last several years under extreme loads and
...super demanding requirements it supports the ability to create cloud
services composer both stateless and statefull micro services
it has support for hyper scale out deployments self healing
...management as walls orchestration of code updates
and were released the service fabric sdk make available on both windows as well as
linux systems the first download that will be available this week
...addition to supporting actor you also be able to...to build great solutions that run in a multi
...we have a great so talks later today we're going to more detail on it.
...think about building great sas applications one of the things that sort of fundamental
...building those is to be able to do great data management and
asher supports a wide variety of data storage and management solutions you
...use pretty much every commercial or open-source data management offering on asher
and microsoft also optimizes and
delivers both relational and no sequel data solutions as highly available
manage services that you can basically deploying use
...sequel database offering is one of our most popular offerings it's a cloud native
databases...service is highly available durable and fault tolerance enables
you to store and manage data without having to worry about infrastructure
patching software updates for backups that's all built-in as part of service you can
...sequel database in just seconds and run it literally anywhere around the world and you
can set up a sequel database to actively jill replicate transactions across multiple
...regions while you're doing...enabling automatic fail over support
within your applications as well as geographic scale-up we've...some great new features the
...databases over the last few months like elastic
...support which enables you to shards skill out sequel databases...petabytes and
size and in memory call-in support which gives you ...
hundred x performance improvements for many core data scenarios
and because again...databases offered as a manage service as opposed to
just a database and side of em developers are able to host scale and use databases
and a true cloud native way in fact up to one hundred sixty thousand sequel databases
...crock created or draught every single-day using
...for a wide variety different scenarios with I do is actually just talk about
...nice video of one of the customers...sequel database actually
...over ten thousand sequel databases running on asher today this is esri
who's leading provider of...information services
software...role video talk about other take advantage of.
Technology off-site locations analytics...history has been
...microsoft measure march from the very beginning days and we built a...offering
...art jess online using microsoft bashed esri uses as
your sequel databases geo...of our users with napkin analytic capabilities
...that's out there but take advantage of this field companies public safety whatever
...also...critical scenarios...government needs to semi-public
...response to a natural disaster people want to know word-based evacuations site
...where to get freshwater...but when they make these maps data
...sometimes it goes viral when that happens we have to be able to scale of
moment's notice enough gases that platform...can do.
Working on things that actually make a difference in people's lives that means.
Samoa.
Recited to announce today a number of great new enhancements
...sequel database service the you can start using immediately these include
deb support which provides the ability to ensure and control encryption
at rest policies within your databases full-text search support
which enables you to run text queries against your data a new capability a particular excited
about ...database pool which enables you to better manage lots of
databases...even lower-cost is perfect process solutions
...challenges for developers that are building sas space applications that serve lots
of bb customers is architected for the right data model...
approaches to use a...database where you have lots of customers sharing the same tables of
...this is...good from a resource cost perspective but introduces
high operational quote complexity in your application now
another approach that many sas apps use is to maintain a separate database per
...to be customer this provides great data isolation...that
...two companies data is ever stored the same database but
in the passes typically more expensive since each database uses a separate
set of resources today we're really excited to introduce our new elastic database
pool support which gives you the best of both worlds
...elastic database pool all enables you to maintain
completely isolated databases for each of your...to be...but
...allows you to aggregate all the resources necessary to run those resources
are databases into a common resource pool this allows you to smooth out the
peaks and dips of different databases within your sat up a
...end up using for fewer resources to run your application and the end result is that
it saves you lots of money also improving the overall operational complexity of running
...to do is invite lore onstage to...often action?
...some great new updates with as
your sequel database and sas developers are going to love this stuff.
...status talked about you can let asher dynamically
manage your database resources using elastic database...
The best part is this
...save you money when you first create a cool one of the decisions
...to make is what databases should you even put in the pool.
Weaver moved a lot of this guesswork.
We're using machine learning behind-the-scenes to produce a list of recommended
databases to go into a pool going-to-take that list of databases and...adam.
want these databases to dynamically use a pool of resources.
So, we have
these visualizations that help us properly size what that pool should look like.
Based on the databases that we selected.
But, it's also very important is that you can
...the minimum and maximum performance characteristics of all
of your databases and basically what this means is any
database can have a spiking performance but they're not going to
end up being a noisy neighbor to any of the other databases in the pool.
Now you don't have to worry about what size...going to give your
database us as zero sthree sone.
Just let asher dynamically figure that out for you...have the best cost
for your company you get the best application performance your customers.
Let's go through some developer stuff.
We have this reports and this is a report for the fabric
him company and the it allows franchise owners to see how
their stores are performing.
The really cool thing about this report is that it's a
...live data from all of the databases in
are cool we had thirty databases and it's using a single
connection string and the single query.
In a few weeks
we're going to deliver in preview elastic database query.
And, creating a report with a
single connection string against a group of databases will be a simple as a select star.
And, finally how do you manage updates and changes when you're in
a sas world you have tens hundreds
...of databases how do you make updates to
all of those databases, for example, with our world we may want to
restrict the rows of data so that each franchise owner only
sees the data...the stores that they...well.
Answer...database delivered role level security sometime ago we want to
implement that but that's going to require change to all of our databases.
...any database chains.
Any schema chains.
Maybe you want to do a maintenance update
...use the new elastic database job.
Will take our standard tc
...that we know and love and we're going to just submit this
role click correctly submit this as a job?
To our pool.
...are less for lower-level security so once
...run my work
as dot leisure do all the rest of the work I don't have to write my
custom script that loops through all the databases I don't have to
manage retry logic I don't have to think about how I'm going to scale this
...tens and hundreds and thousands
of databases answer takes care of all of that for me I can use
this for maintenance jobs like rebuilding
indexes I can use this for other standard statistics updates
or just one-time updates any kind of update like that.
And, after this completes running.
It's already almost complete against all of our databases.
And, if we just give it a second and we refresher report hopefully
martina only sees the rows of data for the stores that she owns.
So, now you've got these fantastic new tools.
That will help really build robust sas applications using as
your sequel database thank you.
So, you see routing
...a great enhancements to our overall data story in terms of enabling you to store
operational allies datawhether it's in a single database or across thousands up
...which gears now and talk also now about how you can use analytics on top of that data...
unique world right now in terms of the expectations people have around intelligent apps
in companies that embrace analytics will be much more content a competitive in this
...economy than those who don't your data
combine with analytics enables you to answer
business critical questions and build much better apps questions like what are the products with
customers already purchased something from you want what's the likelihood of a customer yours churning
...the warning signs you should watch out for before they do so what is the price elasticity of
your products and services how you optimize for that doses sufficient product availability
for the upcoming holiday or for special promotion be able to answer these questions
accurately and use that insight to improve your applications can transform your business now
in the past answer questions like this was painful data warehouses took months to
set-up and integrating...systems heart.
What as...we now provide of suite of a
highly engineered analytic services that make answering these types of questions easy
...enables you'd basically maximise the value of each by the
data that your application stores and processes each of these services on-the-fly can be provision and
minutes and compose together they provide complete full solutions?
And, today I'm excited to announce to new passer services that were launching the complement
this existing offering even further...it even easier to unlock insights from data.
Our new sequel database service makes it easy for anyone to set up a data
warehouse to aggregate in-store data just minutes...lastly scale
...data...how service to store petabytes of data independently
scale compute to match whatever resources you need a to
...or delores offering makes it easy to interactively query and
visualized all the data stored within it as well as operational
...machine learning on top of like to show quick video of it action.
Imagine how could you make your business more intelligent using data...
to the digital customers using a services come from how can you engage them better improve customer
With discounts affect your infantry much.
Imagine you could you...these questions and intelligently project that.
...question moi.
Most servants then you have any
...but now you can...unlimited put you out your question.
Deducing sequel data...sequel data...services easy generate...be launched in
The industry's first part data warehouse that can grow will shrink to any size and second.
Which you can use to intelligently onset any question using data?
Easily import data for any data automated data pipelines
Exceed as well as on premise applications
...and you can easily create reports against what is visualizing simply.
Connect microsoft...data...suggests that.
Also...to easy-to-use predictive...as you machine learning and now
...petabyte scale...applications
...on my...is analyzed customer product moi.
Assessed...race you can expose machine learning api is that your apps control to more
intelligent...interact with your customers and.
The...what
...second scale-up and...ionized machine learning to tap into unlimited query...
So, you can visualize and explore unlimited scenario.
The pouch...has never been greater.
Using our new sequel data warehouse
service you can easily stand-up and aggregate data from any source.
You can archive data from your operational sequel or no sequel databases you also
than aggregate that data from on premises data like sap system
or dynamic system you can also easily aggregate data from a do cluster and,
be able to import any type of data from that...your data...in the data warehouse you
can easily visualized and interact with it using our new our biif service
provides a rich way you can visualize your data and ask questions of your also
run reports against as well as stand-upand, use
the machine learning to create predictive models on top of that data the one of things that makes our machine learning
service so powerful is that once you create a predictive model with it you can
...it as an api that your apps can now call
and use and this basically means the more data you get the smarty...and creates a virtual
...look really allows you to build some truly amazing systems.
The other data well-to-do warehouse offerings in the market todayand, the idea is to see
the good uplift with...red shift offering
...a little bit I'm talking about how now as your is even better unlike red shift you
...independently adjust the amount of compute and,
storage that you use with the sequel data warehouse
this allows you to reduce costs and pay only for you actually need.
You can automatically scale-up what your data warehouse in
seconds this is a big difference versus red shift
...typically takes hours or even days to re scale your data warehouse...data world skills
...read-only mode with perf degradation
...increase in decrees pretty much it will.
...doesn't have the ability to pause a cluster so,
unlike sql data warehouse where you can pause when you no longer need your data where else and pay
only for storage this...to reduce costs and pay only for you actually need.
A great example of that might be when the end of the...the quarter you need to data
...no longer needed just turn it off and you're having to pay for anything.
Our sequel data warehouse runs not just in as you can also be deployed
in run in on premises environment unlike others
...compatibility and feature set perspective sequel data where else provides a full
sequel experience...you to build super powerful applications with these
for really excited about what sequel data warehouse delivers we think is really
a perfect opportunity for you to build and analyze data in a really rich way
allow every developer to get your insights from the data they have.
...exciting...every business out there is to use the internet of
things to transform how we build products and how they engage with customers and we
have some fascinating use cases of io t solutions built now on...
...adding io t sensors to all of their vehicles to improve the
overall car owner experience and they've built a coyote back in solution on...
to collecting process all this data then...connecting it with the customer information that they
already store within apps they own inside their own on premises datacenters and providing a
full complete solution rockwell automation has...biggest energy super
majors out there...basically now running unmanned internet connected gas
...each dispenser emits realtime management information which they can
basically then use machine learning on top of to detect anomalies and predict one proactive,
proactive maintenance needs to be done on machines and my favorite examples probably
the nfl most teams the nfl now use the access
...thunder cloud platform to record analyze
share demon player data in your...during the game.
This...solution runs on...an additional providing real-time statistics analysis on
plates it also records...codes and uploads video
they can be used for...game analysis let's walk through some of the canonical services
...you can use and as your to build these types of...back ends
art using the as your event...a service which released just last fall you can now
...process tens of millions of io team messages per second.
You can use the
...stream analytic service which we may generally available this month to perform near
real-time analytics on top of these io
...messages and you could operational allies it using a combination of our
...to create rich data visualization dashboards of the stream data.
You can awfully now store the raw data or more commonly a subset of the data inside
in these databases that we run inside algebra you can now
...on the raw data within our new data like service that...making available
...this week this new data like service that we're announcing today is really a revolutionary
way to store and process data we've built the new data
...service using more than a decade of real-world learning's
...managing...bytes of data for own microsoft services and ...
the daily service enables you to store literally an infinite amount of data you can create accounts that store
exploits a content with individual files that are up to a petabyte in size.
And, this infinite capacity allows you to keep data in its original form whether
it's coyotes data log files for any other non relational structure.
You can enron high throughput low latency analytic jobs
analyze and process this data at any scale you don't have to worry about setting up
or managing your own clusters to do this instead you can focus on a task at hand
that you want to get accomplished and the service automatically scale out for
...and apply the appropriate resources to get it done the service provides
built-in enterprise great security support enabling to securely lock-down control
...access to any data you store within it...things about the data like service
is that exposes data using the standard who do phd
...api and this enables you actually leverage any analytic
software already out there that supports each...allows you,... run standard
...do jobs...workloads on top of anything's stored inside the data
like you can take advantage of the and...or applications using our new revolution
...distribution and be able now have those skill out
and query against literally exploits of content you...stand-up and use bm hosted cloud
...as well as important works clusters to access and run analytics stored inside the data
like as well as gives you maximum flexibility
enables you to drive even more insight from the data that you ultimately store.
So, as are now has within the richest analytic capabilities
of any clap enables you to build intelligent apps that are highly differentiate
for your customers and this morning I talk about some of these types of applications you can do with
thatyou can use to drive your business disrupt businesses or grow profits.
This technology...can also be used to really change the world in
on business ways as well...of the like to do is invite onstage customer
badger who's doing just that and it's just giving you basically
optimize philanthropic giving campaigns a and help
...funnel money into good causes...do is invite
...onstage to talk about what they do and how they're doing it without...
Great good-morning.
This is what I'm going to talk to-you about today this is what we've built
on the platform we call it the give...
It's a set of complex algorithms that will fundamentally change the way you and I
interact with causes that we care about is going to change the way we give.
to give you some context me tell you a little bit about our company first where based in the uk and
where the largest social given platform to enable people to raise money and
do amazing things for the causes and for the charities that they care about some people decide
to do the marathon obviously recently people with throwing buckets of cold water on top of the
head all in the name of charity and we've been fortunate in having around twenty
three million people from over a hundred and sixty countries in the world?
Do this and they've raised in excess of three billion dollars for charity
and for good causes and this is taken us a lot closer to our goal which is to ensure that
every great...gets the funding that it requires now we live in a world where we
have billions of people who have that natural desire to give?
And, if everyone did that we would eradicate poverty.
We would put cancer out of business now...team had the task of trying to
understand why that isn't happening using analytics using machine
learning and getting a real understanding as to how we think and how we make that decision to give and
our analytics has identified three key things that are product needed to
use data for the first is that it needed to change giving from
being a transactional activity to something that's far more engaging it also
needed to be personal of course it needed to be social after
...we sold some of the biggest problems as human species by connecting with each
other and collaborating but at the heart of all of this is that we needed to
make giving personal which for us means we need to understand what you specifically
care about traditional ways of trying to address personalization would use things like
look-alikes or collaborative filtering but in this space that doesn't work what
you care about a specific to you if you care about cancer or beating cancer
icon find somebody who looks like you and say that they also care
about cancer everybody has something specific that they care about however using
machine learning and graph theory on this platform we've managed to
crack that problem in fact what we've done is we've built a machine
does that those three specific things first of all it understand how
you specifically want to give giving isn't just about money
it understands whether you want to give time or
whether you want to give effort secondly the algorithm can
work out specifically what you care about and it also understands that what you
care about changes it's a moving database it's not static it
...your circumstances change as
your associations change and the more interactive you become?
An lastly my most favorite part of the algorithm is that it understands how
to interact with you specifically with you to make giving more engaging and
remove those barriers that might exist to stop you from giving now we couldn't have
done is without the is your platform where small
team of scientists and engineers and what is your platform really allowed us to do
was focus intensely on our goal we don't have a team of operations experts
...can managing huge cluster of what you...machines in the cloud but this platform
was ideal for us and these are the components that we used and this is how we
architected them essentially had three core processes we had a
batch process which runs nightly a real-time process and approaches that allowed us to put our
...in front of the product?
And, the...batch process is the backbone
for everything that we do and at the center of it is hd
insight this is where we do all of our large calculations this is where we build the give
graph that I showed you earlier so essentially we take all of our data we uploaded into
blob storage...spin up the clusters and do all
of our calculations and once that's done the...a put down in the datas moved
on toas your table storage and that same time we have a
real-time service that helps us keep this product interactive...providing data to the
machines so that it can learn and it can continue to become more effective these are
...mailboxes and your service...for that of course we have visual websites
...or the...web app which is where we put our idi
...and where the product has access to it and all of this
manifests itself on the product itself this is what...feed looks like this is what
...our and what's exciting is that this is where we
are seeing giving move from a transactional activity to more engaging we're seeing
people be for more interactive informal social connecting collaborating
about the causes that they care about the charities that are important to them?
And, as I conclude
...can't emphasize enough how much this how much of an impact this is
going to have...really in a fantastic position because this platform has allowed us
to focus exclusively on I'll go to ensure that every great
...gets the funding that requires thank you.
The opportunity to build applications that can change the world has
never been greater each of you now has access to cloud resources that
were unimaginable just a few years ago there's never been a better time to
be a developer and I'm really looking forward to seeing what-you built thank you very much.
All right we'll move to the next chapter of
our platform innovation office.
There are three core concepts.
In the transformation of office to...platform.
The first one is about the user experience.
We're opening up
the office user experience for all of your applications in fundamental
ways so that your applications can show up in the context of what
...billion plus users of office...in office create
staff do get stuff done collaborate communicate we want
you to be able to build applications that fit naturally into those context
second we want to go beyond single applications their
api in data silos to a semantically rich...
of data that is available...you to be able to consume.
As well as extent.
We want to have the capability to reason over that
...and...intelligence into your applications so that not only does
it drive new features or more importantly
...engagement in your applications so those are the tree
concept that fundamentally change office so we want to give you a quick tour of that
so that you can look at what your applications can do to exploit these capabilities and
...for that I just want to interviews...from our officeteam to show you some of those I rob...
So, how can we get started by talking about how
we're moving from office from mas to office with
partners that's great that's...write-in we're looking at here is word
this is office sixteen when thirty-two what we see is a solution from
...you sign scott was talking about them earlier they do digital signatures
and they've integrated the our of their service directly and office using a
...new modern web at in framework it's built on top of html five
and javascript communicates the document through javascript object model let's switch gears and look
at another one this is an add-in that we're building partnering with sap that makes it easy for
me while I'm building a spreadsheet like my product inventory information to pull
information directly from sap this is built on top of sap for gateway
from microsoft when the great things about the new add-in framework is that
it works across platforms so let's switch over to the browser
and excel online I get to see the same spreadsheet with the same great
add-in experience running in both places it's the same out on
that goes everywhere office goes that's exactly right and in fact let's take a
look at excel for the and what we see is exactly what you want to have
the same solution hosted in excel for the showing the same add-in running for
...and this will be released in upcoming months but let me just show you how I could use that?
To connect sap or click connect and it does exactly what you want which is
...my on premise safety server
...the content out and deliberate directly inside of my spreadsheet running on the.
Let's talk about something very different let's talk about making a presentation
when I'm doing this of course want
a constant source of high-quality professional photographs that I can integrate into my slide
deck picket me is a relatively new company that is building just such a service and is
...an add-in here that lets me search through the photos in those service and
...them directly with in powerpoint one of the key things about this
add-in model is that it's a road map for how we're going to do
...going forward so let's take a look at the newest member of the office family
sway this is a tool for interactive story-telling that runs great on the
web and renders beautifully mobley and we've integrated a
set of services that make it easy for me to polling contents we've
integrated with picket and will be delivering and upcoming months?
...services...be delivering and upcoming...the exact same framework and
add-in model that runs across all of the end points for office that's word excel
powerpoint and outlook let's take a look at people working in outlook professional
users handling and managing all their email dealing with a great deal
of information they want to stay up-to-date on who are all these people that were talking to what
we're showing here is...add-in from linkedin that makes it easy for me to do that it
...the users off the to in cc line it shows them to
me directly in the context of my email so I don't have to leave the flow of how I'm doing my work
we sales force has built a very similar thing that...from the to in cc line but also looks
up the companies that are showing up on the mail thread so I get to see the people and
...them...sales force but I can see the accounts and I can go right into the
opportunities and take action from here within outlook without leaving the flow of my
...it's been great to be working with the sales forcing because they're really
...all of the extensions we have across the entire surface area of office
ba and excel and outlook or in other
areas and build the business process right into the collaboration
...communications infrastructure that's fantastic dasi absolutely outlook is not
just about mail outlook is also about my appointments in my calendar
ing and it has all that information is structured way below the important things for me is not as
being the meeting but getting there on time or partnering with over to build a solution that does exactly
this so here's an ad in that...has built...I can set and
huber ride reminder to show up ahead of time and make sure that I get to where I need to go
as we switch over here to the iphone what I actually see is I've got a reminder for
mover seeing slide to get a ride so I'll go ahead and do that it brings up
huber and it's my pick-up location the cool thing is that
it got my destination because that lived in outlook so outlook knew where I needed to be
...huber knows where I need to go that's great so that
shows you how applications that you...throughout office
they extend beyond any single application now let's talk a little bit
about this graph how are we...and exposing the grafted developers,
yeah, that's actually pop it open and take a look at exactly what it looks like so this week
at build we're announcing a preview of the unify
api endpoint for office three sixty-five api is this builds on top of the
file mail calendar workloads that we delivered last fall and what it does is make it
easy for developers to get to this data in a unify consistent way so
we just popping open a little api explorer tool that can show us what are some of those request
and response patterns look like so what we use a developer have to do in order to get access to this
rich data what you can see is the urls a pretty simple
...dot microsoft dot com version number and the tenant that I
and connecting to so make it easy for me in this example
...query active directory together list of users I'm karen from users for a particular
departments in this case operations what I get back is exactly what...expect
clean well formatted easy-to-understand json every developer in the room has a
whole toolkit that can parse this and use it to build great solutions but the point is
that this is actually a graph so I can go from an individual user
drill into their files all I have to do to get to the files from one drive for business is
...lash files on the end of the url and from
...data documents coming back from one drive these are just the files that the
login user as permission is and that's the powerful concept which is you no longer are going
to different applications for different data you're not going to active directory for users in groups and then
two-one drive for files but you're able to traverse the entirety of the
...with these api is exactly right in fact speaking of
groups let's pull up another example office three sixty five has a new concept for unify
modern group that brings together the people and the documents and conversations
...that they're having and we're exposing that through the unify api so I can query
the active directory for groups and I can navigate through them to find
...files that belong to those group so here we actually see stick on a slaps files it brings
up the files associate with that group again trims to the login user?
Now this notion of login...a really common pattern for people building solutions so we've actually made
it super easy there's a me token that you can stick in your url to just get back the data for the
login use and that's probably very important because everything here is
...through the policies and axles that you put into...so in some sense the
...token gives you access for the user using the applications credentials exactly
right and because now I have access to my information I can go and look at my
calendar just slash events on the end of url and that brings back appointments that are
...my outlook calendar and same idea to get to messages
last messages and boom I'm in my inbox coming from exchange and it's just that easy
awesome so how can we talk about the last concept which is how do we go
from here to really building the...
of intelligence inside of your applications sure so,
this is powered by the office graphs and the thing about the office...is we talked about data
we talked about...and we really talked about how we can use that to drive a whole
other set of insights we know who are the people that
conversations the meeting in the organizations what we can do with that is provide additional insights
...they can use that in the preview here to query the...to get information out
...addition were delivering a first party app in the shape of delved
that actually provides me every day with information about what am I working on it helps me
search in discover the content that my colleagues are using.
There's something funny going on.
Keep going overt.
Ok, so, here I am looking at delves and, what I see is
exactly what you'd expect some cards and contact...will help me stay up-to-date on
what my colleagues are doing so I see and excel notebook that is coming...one drive
the let's me see here's what my boss peltier some caped guys here's an attachment that lives
in email but we've been working with partners to imagine what will it look
like when we have additional third-party signals coming to the...how can they get into this
notification stream what we see here are opportunities so
that's a card from sales force and that's exactly right this is a carven sales were showing the
amount showing information about moans account etc I can navigate down
here's information coming from twitter and believe that we see information coming from
...people are collaborating boards I can navigate directly through and get to thatand,
let's actually scroll down a little bit further and what we see is a purchase order coming from
dynamics ax that looks like a super important one so it was...delve made easy for me to take
action on it right so this is no longer now information that is inside of the office
...that's based on the data of our apps but people are able to extend the
graph with additional edges and nodes that's all surfacing
in doubt that's exactly right wonderful thank you so much ranking very much?
That gives you a flavor for how offices fundamentally changing in fact there's one other
sdk that we're launching in addition to the office graph which is what
web sdk for skylight where the presence information where the ability to
embed...side of your applications video chat and messaging is
now possible so you can build a web app mobile app using sky presence information
...embedded inside of your apps this fundamental change.
That we're making...this fundamental platform shift of office
where the users the one billion plus users of office are available for you is
developers the semantically rich graph that is available for you to consume
...extend and to drive additional engagement
through intelligence we believe is going to change the very fundamental nature of
what office is to becoming really a platform
...from us and from you together.
I know you all...very patiently to hear about windows.
And, it's now time to talk about windows.
Windows ten.
As I said.
Is not just another release a windows
is a new generation of windows?
It is windows
built for this era of more personal computing.
Where mobility of the experience across devices is
what is paramount not just the mobility of the device?
It's...such that users can interact with a variety
of devices that are going to be powered by windows in the most
natural ways it could be taught
...can be inks speech mouse and keyboard or even
hologram it is also...foundation of trust.
When we talk about more personal it becomes even more important to know
that...data that you are giving the
system is being used to benefit the use of
...of foundational things that drive more personal computing for us?
It is a very different windows in terms of
how we deliver it how we keep it alive.
It's a service we want-to make sure.
That for every...here you have.
The wide...why
...user base that you are applications can target we
also have a unify platform everything from raspberry
pied to the holographic computer is one developer platform that
means you're scales apply across all of the places windows
And, lastly.
...one unify store.
That means the economic return for what you do on windows.
Spans.
The entire install base and the growing.
Device family of windows.
So, I'm really excited about where we are in this
johnnie pariah most excited about what.
We together are going to do in the coming year with windows
stand better all the video.
...consumer and...enterprise customers.
...available riyadh.
...that...and earlier phase...any other time in...of...
Follow developers
...so great to be back here build to talk about windows ten.
Factitious shared that are aspiration is for customers for end-users to love using windows
...what we also have this aspiration for you to
...developing for windows ten.
Our goal is to make windows ten the most attractive development
platform ever enabling you to build the most innovative applications,
applications
that your customers never before possible.
Integrate...homa into your apps.
Integrate xbox live ensure apps giving your customers awards
and achievements or bring them a wife with the avatar.
And, natural user at interactions to your apps like penn.
...speech turn your apps in the hologram.
With windows chan.
...targeting the
broadest device family ever from devices with small screens.
So, large-screen...gone beyond and all-in-one pc to
our large-size...displays the surface hub.
...devices with no screen at all like the internet of things.
Or hollow...
We're talking about one platform.
A single out
a single binary they can run across all of these devices.
When we look at the search terms?
In the store.
We compare...people are searching for an phones to with searching for a pc's.
We see that forty percent of the search terms are exactly the same.
Customers are looking for your apps in all of these places.
With apple you choose to invest in
...or...os...google you choose to invests
...android or chrome os.
Windows is the only ecosystem.
...what you bring your apps to all of these devices efficiently.
...are many ways to get apps on windows.
What's talk about the windows store.
...come from the windows store.
Come with the set...promises to the end-user your customers.
For end-users applications in the windows...very
easy to discover not only within the store itself but
...summa show you how windows applications can be discovered throughout the windows experience.
Apps from the windows store.
Will be easy and fast to install?
And,...you wants.
And, they will never junk up your system.
Commerce...windows star will be convenience and trusted with
a wide variety of global payment insurance.
Not just the credit cards we are use here
in the us but payment instruments like always pay for china.
And, today we're announcing carrier billing.
Not only for windows phones but for all windows devices.
And, windows what the largest carrier billing footprint any ecosystem.
With connections two-ninety mobile operators.
Our experience with phone's this is great.
For our customers that don't have credit cards but you have phones.
And, this is great for developers because our experience with
phones that emerging markets.
Application purchases have gone up by a factor of eight times.
When carrier
...is enabled and now it's available...windows devices?
The new windows store.
Offer new business models and ways...monetize for all of our windows developers
including subscriptions affiliate referrals and updated advertising
...support for video ads and install tracking one set of tools one
set of processes...you to reach customers across all of these devices engage with
the customers all over the planet with reviews and ratings
and other tools that are available in the windows store.
And, today we're introducing the windows store for business.
Businesses in schools can customize the windows store.
Hiring applications in the public catalog
...want to make more easily discoverable recommend to their employees are students.
And, the windows store for business will support business payment methods
by purchase orders opening up a new vein of opportunity
for windows developers to engage with windows enterprises worldwide.
...make all this worthwhile for developers we know we need to get windows
tend to be broadly adopted quickly so we started by making it
available as a free upgrade for the first-year.
And, now...investing
...making it easy for consumers and businesses to adopt windows ten
worldwide.
Today
we're sharing our goal our goal is that within two or three years of windows
...release zero-b one billion devices running windows ten.
No, other platform version in any ecosystem
is available on one billion devices current estimates
for google placate cat is that a little over five
hundred million devices.
...lower than that.
With windows ten
...one billion devices ready to run your applications.
Now we've already working with many of you and your
...embracing this new universal windows platform working and doing things
you can't do...any other platform.
We're delighted that companies like disney netflix
...twitter so many more working with us to build amazing applications for
the one billion devices that well-run windows ten.
Let's take a look at some of the work by these partners.
Five-star quite highlighting the work being done by usa today which is been a great windows developer
...a great partner today they have a separate code base for
phone application...pc application they want to bring these code
...they can focus on great quality
and great functionality and take that application to new windows devices.
So, here.
You see the usa today is live tile from their new universal windows application.
On this pc suppress great work with touch and
keyboard shortcuts.
The application uses are standard
...standard platform controls so resize is an
...as the application is resize on the desktop snapping
...do more work.
Now I can never get enough reading about dupes basketball team
sorts go there and you can see here the app the article
foes greatly in the foes great in this size
window now this application is also using our platform capabilities to
automatically store state in the cloud...the state of the me reading this article is
...all these divide all my windows devices or other devices that might want to
access the same state so now I pick up...windows phone.
At the same binary running...the same live tile.
...and the articles opening up to
the exact same place leveraging state those automatically
shared to the cloud one binary one code base all working across phones have
...pc now usatoday...to bring your application to the xbox.
...do...reading of articles on the xbox they want to
tailor the application filter.
The application down...video feeds so they invest in one-hour
...universal windows application code base and here it
is running on the xbox.
Filtered down to just video...navigating in...general and
...navigate down I see the same video controls that...available across the windows ten
platform.
Navigating down further and...I get recommended video...investment is one
universal windows application they now have phones tablets
pc's interactive television all covered with one code base and one...
Now let's take a look at the work ten sense done with their we chat application
we chats and incredible phenomenon just crossed five hundred-million monthly active users
...forty percent year over year they've been a great application for windows phone
users.
Here they are on my windows phone.
Ten send wanted to bring we chat to windows
...and tablets so they
...investment in their silverlight application on the phone
...team spent about approximately one month they now have a universal windows app
...runs great on the phones and will also now we available on the desktop with
...experiences for the desktop so let's look at we chat on the desktop?
Now on the phone...notice shannon sent me a message.
I have which at installments pc now we can access that new
mentions from the notification center.
I click on the notifications center message from which...same binary running both places.
Open the message and...asking for the file and here they've done some tailoring to
accepts drag-and-drop from the desktop all
with one universal windows application that's running across these devices.
For usa today and we chat...just a couple of
them many great apps coming to the universal windows platform if you mitch joel
...fury will join us and show how universal one is apps are going
to enable you to do things you never thought possible on a phone.
Analysis...going to join to talk about
how universal windows apps you never thought possible on hall...
Now partners like but these are giving us great feedback as
engage across all these devices with the universal windows platform.
...they can...sufficiently everywhere.
It...crap...a great game of...frac three
...tours developing...is four times faster and developing for
android ios.
Let me just.
Say thank you for your early engagement and the universal
windows platform so we can bring your applications to life.
So, that was about.
That was all about new universal windows apps.
But, today we...talk also about your current code.
Your current apps.
Windows...always embraced a wide variety of technologies to build rate
And, today we're going to announce.
For new ones.
For new ways to leverage your existing code and skills.
For new ways to reduce the cost
an effort making it easy
...bring applications the windows store.
For new ways to...one billion windows
ten customers at home at school.
Let's start.
By talking about the web.
Many of you have websites that provide great
...your customers today I'm announcing that you can reuse
your current server hosted website coding tools.
And, take advantage of the rich capabilities of the universal windows
platform.
Have your website send notifications to give your website
...tile have your website integrate reports on a do went out purchases
...with xbox live and more?
This will help your websites reach new customers and the
...windows customers in new ways.
But, see this an action.
So, to demonstrate this we're going to use a website twenty-two tracks which deejays
across europe used to exchange...it's a very rich apple
...website uses web gl.
Brief loads.
Dot to the browser re sizing it's a great website
what john is a registered website with the windows store and then I have installed.
That application on this machine.
...there is and it's going to open up
as an application the web the server host web code can detect whether the
code is executing insider browser tab or inside
an application frame when it's inside...application frame.
In...call the whole universal windows platform so now when I close
the browser tab the websites gone but now that it's...app when I...
The app twenty-two tracks can now...and notification click on
the notification and I come back to their app likewise now the
...tracks is user can...running as an app they
can efficient conveniently offer in out purchases to
other customers for the music leveraging the commerce capabilities of the windows
store so this is just fantastic wedding website developers leverage all
...server host code.
And, take advantage of the capabilities of
...platform and the windows store.
So, now the second technology I want to announce today.
To enable you to bring new applications to the windows store.
Is actually the most popular technology within the windows development community?
Dot net and...thirty-two.
There's over sixteen million dot net and
...thirty-two applications being used every month.
In the windows user base.
Ranging from some amazing games to some of the most important
line-of-business apps used worldwide visit testament to the great work being done by windows
developers
...so excited to announce that will be adding support for
bring your dot net and...thirty-two apps into the windows store
and take advantage of all of the new universal windows platform capabilities.
Show you how this works.
...use app...used by...by customers worldwide.
One of the best when thirty-two applications ever adobe photoshop.
So, here you see adobe photoshop elements.
In the windows store.
Now I...earlier the promise the windows store makes the end-users
...applications will be very efficiently installed on
installed on never junk up your system.
We know the same time
...thirty-two applications can do anything to windows system.
So, we've learned from app...enterprise application virtualization
technology we've adopted it through the windows store so now
when thirty-two and dot net applications come down from the windows store and they
run and isolated way from the rest of the systems we can deliver on that promised
...deliver a great and user experience.
So, here is photoshop you can see it is the full photoshop experience with great
performance note prove that...with a full limits my photoshop capabilities.
Helping...out here so there you go but
all come down from the windows store.
And, it's very exciting share.
That later this year adobe we building bringing photoshop elements and
premiere elements to the windows store.
So, the...great support for apps built using web code.
Dot net and...thirty-two code.
...use your current code bases extend them using windows
...new platform capabilities and the...customers
across the one billion windows ten devices.
Now the third technology I'm announcing today
will enable developers to reuse nearly all of the java
and cplus-plus code from android phone
app to create apps for phone's running windows ten.
To make this possible.
Windows phones will include an android subsystem.
Were...app can be written that takes advantage of the android code but
also the extensions you right in the windows platform to really divide
the windows user to show you how this works please welcome...stage agnes.
My name...nascar...and one of the project of years working on the
technology that will enable you to build great windows apps by
reusing a lot of the code you have written for android here I have an android device.
And, on it I'm running the choice hotels
up choice hotels is the highest rated up and it's category makes it
very easy for travelers to find a great hotel.
They're going to switch to windows phone.
On this windows phone I am also running the choice
hotels app.
This app is reusing the code you just so running on the other device.
I'd like to look for hotels nearby.
The app is taking advantage
of the windows location api to find.
Hotels in san francisco ca.
Okay.
...have a switch to...device which.
Well, let's try that again.
Research right as I scroll through the results.
You can see that the windows graphics in touch just work
and the app is running smoothly it's running the windows security container to
...trustworthy experience for windows users.
I'd like to go back.
And, as I hit the back button.
Please note that the apps navigation...integrated with the windows navigation model.
I'd like to selected different city so I'm going to type in.
Seattle.
With a built-in windows keyboard.
So, I have just shown you.
However, nap can take efficiently reuse
existing code to deliver a great experience on windows.
And, tomorrows keynote we will show you how you
can light up your apps experience with native windows features such as
lifestyles and with microsoft services thank you...back to
So, windows chance can enable you to reuse.
Your web code your dot net and when...code your?
Android java and cplus-plus code
to build amazing new applications bringing the...over.
Extending it putting in the windows store.
And, reaching one billion windows ten customers.
Finally.
The fourth technology table
...new universal windows applications.
Is objectives c?
So, today we're announcing that you'll be able to
compile the same objective c code.
That's being used
...ios applications within visual studio on windows.
Enable you to leverage that code.
An extended
with the capabilities only found on the windows platform.
...take a...
So, here and this directory we have
and ios application math dream.
You can see here the x code project file
for math dream you can see the natives
...zip files for the uri
your the classes directory you can see that dot m files.
For the objective c.
Using it's okay we're announcing today we've converted the x code project
file into a visual studio solution so
let's open up here.
In visual studio.
You can see full support for this visual studio projects.
Objective c.
Great syntax highlighting support expect
from visual studio including highlighting all of the weirdness objectives c.
We've taken this application.
And, now we can debugged and execute this tablet app on windows.
You can see...a relatively sophisticated app that uses ui
...uses core animation on windows.
The performance is good but also works with mouse and touch.
Can do very complex arithmetic to do that?
But, actually that's the wrong answers...what's the justice to the right number of
apples and you can see not only...correctly do...
What is application has been extended so offer me
and xbox live achievement for doing the proper map equation?
Now you might be wondering if this actually works.
Will work for more complex app?
Now usually announces kind of
thing would say coming soon well in this case it's different
we've been working with some great development partners and
...applications to windows using this technology already.
And, today I'm very excited to share.
But, this is how king.
Broad candy crash saga...windows phone.
The app has four-and-a-half star reviews forty thousand
reviews king brought the app to windows phone the very fast time the market
very few code modifications and it's a great app and now can
will be releasing more titles for windows ten soon.
So, there's actually one more thing we're going to do.
To help make it easy.
For you to build...
Windows, windows applications.
And, that is we need to get use some grates hardware.
...order to start today by giving everyone here
are brand-new hp...and one.
This is a great device.
Compared to...its thinner...lawyer
has longer battery wife of course it has a touch display and
our encourage everyone here.
To join
the windows insider program engage with us on this platform.
And, help shaping for your needs.
...fleas do the upgrade to windows ten from your hotels wi-fi.
Not...the conference.
today we talked about...one billion windows ten devices
the unique capabilities of the windows ten platform and our commitment to a
broad range of technologies to leverage your skills and
your current code to build great apps.
We've got so much more dot com so please welcome...built your.
All right good morning.
Hello, it's nice to...at...with all of
you so, you got a chance to look at how the universal windows platforms
...enable all of you and tons of other developers to build great
compelling apps and what I'm here to do us terry said is to talk about how we're going to
enhance the windows user experience so that end-users on
lots and lots of devices but in particular I'm going to focus on the pc how
end-users will be able to discover
and engage with all of the apps that you and we right we know
that great technology for building apps is just part of the story you need users to engage
with them so I want to show you some of the work we're doing that's going to make that possible and...I'm going to wrap up with one more
cool demo of how the universal windows platform enables new devices
and new kinds of actions on devices so let me just jump right in and get started so,
I have here a very recent build of windows ten for the pc and I'm going to
begin on the start menu I want to show you some of the work we've been doing to continue to
tweak the design and improve the visuals in the interaction
so you'll see what I've got here we think is pretty close to what we expect to have
when we're done although of course we're going to continue to take feedback from our insiders you'll notice
there's new beautiful live tile animations that helped draw people's
attention to the apps and the app data for the things that they've pinned
you'll notice we've clean the layout up a bit for those of you insiders who
kind of surprised us with your enthusiasm for windows
...aero glass you'll notice the translucent see here's the blur
effect that you saw...windows seven so we're trying to bring some of that field back
we've got the most used apps here we're putting file explore settings our all apps
at the bottom were bringing jump lists back in so you can see here's file explore with
jump listen this work for other apps as well thank you?
But, the thing I wanted sort of focus on a little bit
is this space right here where in this case I have an installed and app for a
little while so the system is going to give us a smart suggestion
for app in the store that is going to be one that suitable for me as I'm using my
pc on the client we know which apps your launching and which apps your installing
...so we're able to communicate with the store and bring down suggestions that are personalize for
you to help users learn about great new apps that are available for them to trout
...their pc and as time goes by we
...that space in a smart way to help script the
users discovery of apps first but then...engagement later so five
installed and app as you see here for a little while that space becomes the recently
installed out the user confine the app they can revisit and if they use it
enough it'll move its way up into the most used section automatically of course at
any time the user can drag from left to right to take any of those apps and pin them as
full live tiles so think of this as the users lifecycle of discovery
and engagement and re-use which we're trying to script right into the start menu?
There's a whole other area that users are engaging with for we want to
bring some beauty and new ideas for how they can get value out of
their pc experience and that is the...screen so I want to show you some of what we're doing on
...to help users discover and engage with the value in
the windows ecosystem so imagine your user and this morning you wake up and you
turn on your pc or your tablet and you get this beautiful...screen when this case
you're using our windows spotlight feature which you could choose to use or not on your
...screen and it provides a service driven personalized stream
of information on your...screen for you so maybe in a week you wake up and
the earth screen looks a little different in this case you say yourself man that is a beautiful
...striking image...your so enthused by it that you move your mouse the upper
right click on the hot spot like what you see here's a place where you have the opportunity
to train our service on which things are interesting to you in this case I
can by find out this is the navajo loops which backs it's a cool looking trail I might vote that I love it and
then I'll get more images like that time goes by one day if you see
...image like this now this is because we are able as I
said to understand on the client what your use of the pc is
an communicate that data to the service to give personally relevant suggestions
...imagine a user who's had windows
ten for six weeks or eight weeks and they haven't used
...on a yet they haven't tried it out and because they haven't tried it out
our services able to provide the client with a set of options that
we can display to help users learn about discovery engage with value in
the windows ecosystem and in this case you see the image that suggestive of core
...others a few more hotspots to give you more information if you click in the upper-left
will give you a preview of what the...tiny you I would be like you could click give
me a try that unlock your pc will reveal the core tiny user experience and now you can
try it out for yourself keep in mind this is personalized and
...informed by what you do on the pc...our user has been using...you're not going
to see this imagine time goes by you get more beautiful images your desktop pc
or your tablet always feels fresh with all this great stuff and then one morning you might see
...image like this as a tablet user.
maybe have not tried out all the capabilities of your tablet to do stuff like beautiful artwork using the
...in fact here's an app that gives you that kind of benefit
that you haven't you so far and there's a few extra hotspots to help you learn about
it when you click in the upper-left...your the fresh paint app that's in the
stores described at any time you could choose to click get it now your
pc you unlock your pc jump right into the store and then you'd be able
to install the app and try it out and then a few days go by and you're back to seeing
your beautiful images we call this feature the windows spotlight and
it's optional any user can turn it on with their
...screen and then get the value of learning about new things in
the windows ecosystem in a way that's tailored for you and also get this beautiful
stream of images on your...screen so that's another way...going to help users
find discover value in the windows ecosystem okay I'm...to show you
that yet another part of our user experience that we've continue to
...with feedback from our insiders which has a lot of relevance to users
discovering and engaging with apps that's core tunnel so of
course we've done lots of demos of...on I'm not going to go through the end-user features of core
...but...show you...ways that core tunnel will assist with
engagement I should quickly point out there's some new you why that we have for
...you all haven't seen yet you'll be getting this
in of a flight coming up soon over here I have access to the core taught at home all
...this out you can see the notebook your reminders your favorite places
of course here is the...the place where she gives you proactive suggestions and
...on your interests you can see I follow microsoft's stock I
follow the mariners baseball team I care about sports news in general
the seattle seahawks so on so...are those are personal interests that I've educated core
...a about which are things that are relevant to meet you'll see how this comes up again
later now what are the really high use cases for that core
...control right there is people typing to ask questions get information but
also to launch apps and we think that's a great relevant way to help people
discover new value as well so imagine I am
a running starwars commander on my pc I've got it installed and I run it a
lot I might start typing into
launch the app and you'll notice in this case there's a new star wars rebels app in the
star wars...family and we're going to promote...the top this new app
that's available for you to install...will point out because you may be sitting there thinkingthat's not that
much promotion we've done some user testing on this and we're going to bulk up that store app
...to provide a little bit more information more along the lines...sign starts we think this is going to be
quite helpful way to discover new apps that are available in
the store now terry mention this
...mention the notion that we care about natural interaction we want core
time to represent a single way for users on windows to
interact with all kinds of capabilities that are built throughout the ecosystem so
we're connecting core...typed natural language and spoken natural
language deeply into your apps we're doing this and two ways this is quite a
bit farther than we did with windows phone before so I want to show you the range of
...sorts of things that are possible I...imagine in one case I want to bring
up the app to do a task with the app and...other case I simply want core trying to get something
done for me using the technology that's part of an app so here's a couple of examples
...all started chat with...on vibrant.
Starting to chat with...and now in this case I gave...natural language
...I said I want to started chat I said it was with...I said I wanted her to do it on
vibrant and in this case she opens up the app
and in my chat context with the previous chatting we were doing like keep going with my
chat so that's sort of a deep app launching kind of task but
there's a whole class of tasks where we want
...to represent being a personal assistant that can
get things done for you even using the capabilities that are written into the apps
that are part of the windows ecosystem so I can ask for thaler to execute
commands in apps and get confirmation right under canvas decor tunnel
...tell...I'm running really late using vibe or.
Ok, message...and on vibe or...and I'm running really late.
Sounds good.
Yes, yep,
message sent ok there we go so you
get the idea here now in this case...ask core
...do something using app and in that case the app you I didn't need to get displayed so core
...canvas was able to do the disambiguation if I want to I could go right here
...click the link to open the app but that's not what I need to do there's
...on a helping me get stuff done okay so I've talked about the
large-screen the start screen...tama there's one other really big featured windows ten that has
relevance this conversation to all of us developers and that is
project spartan project spartan products part, you know,
I have to admit our pr team has been giving me and us a hard time because they say
it's not a great idea to keep saying project spartan when that's not really the name
of the web would you like to hear the name of the new web browser and windows tent ok let's...
Microsoft edge is the browser built for windows ten
...be available on the widest range of windows ten devices and for us the
name refers to the idea of being on the edge of consuming
and creating it refers to the developer notion of being closest to the modern
capabilities of the web so, it is a browser that end-users will think about
forgetting things done for things like note-taking on the internet for a great
way of reading and consuming content and it's a browser that has core
tama built-in so it learns the things that you care about and helps you get things done I'm not going
to go show any that stuff we've shown that before as developers their
few reasons that you're going to care about microsoft edge you're going
to care about the blazing fast core technology that's inside it you'll hear more about that
it talk tomorrow you're going to care that we're writing it as a universal
windows app proving out the platform and you're also going to care because we're going to make it
...users discover and engage with your apps and your
sites so they come over here and show you some of what we're doing there are
come down here to the ee icon on the task bar which now has a completely different
and better meeting that it has for a while and open up microsoft edge
now the first thing that I want to show you that's new is the new tab page...were adding
to microsoft at today and...the task...starting a new tab and starting new web
browsing happens over a billion times a day so this is a heavily used piece of
uri and you'll see here how we're going to take advantage of core
...presence in the browser an understanding of
you a along with an understanding of value
...ecosystem to give users a great way to start there web browsing experience or
discover other things you can see of course I can type to enter webbed address or do a search up
here are my top sites and in some cases there's an app available for the sites in the store
we make that discoverable...available as I scroll down you'll see here some featured apps that were
showing here's a lot of news stories that are
relevant to me in fact my sports favorites that you...and mike stock watch listing core
...those are represented right here in the new...page that's an example of
...tama helping to compose this in a way that's useful to me so
that's new tab and we've been testing this a ton and
were optimistic about its opportunity to
help people discover and connect with work that you all do on the web and
in apps there's another big thing that we're doing and microsoft edge that's
has huge relevance to you and that is enabling users to engage with your
sites and give you a shot at starting to write some web code which you may and put into
and app via a web extensions
built into microsoft edge so I'm going to show you a couple of web extensions
this is html and javascript...web extensions using web standards that people have
been writing for fire fox and chrome for quite a while we've grabbed a couple of these
from chrome with just a few minor modifications and we're letting them up right
here in microsoft edge so the first...any reddit users to we have yes,
come on, you must be reddit users of for those of you who are our reddit
users maybe...some of the other browsers you've tried the reddit enhancement
...which modifies the mark-up on reddit to make it easier to
...images and scroll pages what we've brought that to microsoft edge as I
said just a few changes so as I scroll down here you'll see the web has
been altered via this little pop print here that I can use to expand
and his little pick
...just kills me...as I look at this cute it's a cat or a mouse I don't even know
as I scroll down here you'll see the never-ending reddit modifies the page
...continue expanded as we go it
was virtually no work to take this from the chrome...store and run this
is standards-based html and javascript just running here is part of an
extension now another example which certainly matters in terms of user engagement up here
you'll see we've added a pinterest extension to the browser toolbar and when I
click that this is going to interact with
...mark-up on the page to show all of the images that were generated by the reddit enhancement
...and now I confine tons of things here that are incredibly cute that I might ten-to-one of
the many pinterest cute animal boards that I and I know all of you keepjust for
this sort of thing so with projects part with microsoft edge and
...new support for these extensions you'll see how we're going to enable
people to discover and engage with code that your
propped up on the web and as I said of course you could bring that into and app as well so you've
seen for engagement the start screen the...screen you've seen
...and microsoft edge all helping people discover value
...the windows ecosystem but what I'm going to do is change gears and talk about how the windows
platform and universal windows apps make devices
more valuable to end-users in general we have a
vision an idea that the windows platform and apps written for it should
be able to flex to different screen sizes and different input methods not by
writing separate code but by having a platform that smart enough to do
in fact even dynamically on the same device we call this feature continuum it's a
promise to end-users made along with our oem partners that devices can
...so I want to show you some of the ways that continuum
is evolving and I want to show you some of the ways that your apps can light up a
great continuum experience I'm going to start with eight-inch tablet this is a lenovo thinkpad
it's running...full windows it's got intel compatible part and the first thing you
might notice of course I'm going to use this in tablet...you're looking at tablet...but for those of you
paid attention closely and especially if you've given us feedback
...start in tablet
mode we've simplified here we've made the live tiles bigger this looks very familiar to windows
eight users and the extra stuff you're most use list your
sign in things like file explore settings the
our switch are all over here I can navigate to all apps all apps
...showed nicely in this list we now have jumped lists working in here
in a nice way with animation so on so it's really easy for me to navigate
around my apps of course down here in the tips the system tasks which
are I've got my task switching button which I can use to switch between lots of apps here's
...so that's the excel for windows ten and I'm going to do
...jump into maps and do some navigation in the maps app here and I want to show you how
this will scale to of more full pc like experience so,
here I am in my map I'm...go up here choose
the favorites menu and down here in this panel on the bottom we're first going to
navigate to new york city and I want to point out that the system ui now includes a global
back button so...hit the back button the app navigate back and now...navigate to
...now what I'm going to do I want you to think about me using this
...a very natural touch friendly way but now since...pc
...bring it back to my...I'm just going to docket in here and when I do I want you
to notice how the maps app
experience changes to adapt the panel that was on the bottom when I
...portrait mode is now on the left side and in fact when I,
you know, restore this window I've now got my excel I've got my powerpoint
all here running in a familiar way with windows that I can minimize
and restore in pc mode so that's an example of continuum really helping me flex
on a small tablet the next example I want to show you that's new is here on
this surface pro three where I have a rich complex...app
...is otto desks...it's a high-end heavily used
very popular three-d authoring out and, you know, if you notice the you I've got lots of tool
...and...down here I've got the timeline or...might edit animation
of my three-d character but imagine I'm an artist so I might use this docked with
the big-screen keyboard mouse might use it like this but sometimes I'm going to remove
the keyboard entirely and use it like a tablet and in this case here's...within thirty
...app responding to that change in state in the system...adapting its
...and now I can use touch or I could use the
pen to be able to do things like mark-up right on the character maybe
it maybe I'm now going to be in this note where in this mode where I want take notes for people
...might team share my thoughts on the character the app flex is to take
advantage of the use of the pen and touch as opposed to mouse and keyboard
...that case using when thirty-two now I have one last thing I want to show thank you?
I have one last thing I want to show so far we've shown this continuum
feature working with our shell and with apps on the pc and watching the pc
device flex across these form factors but we have a vision that not only the
pc can benefit from flexibility and use of input devices
and screen sizes so to can the phone so today
we're excited to show for the first-time continuum for
phones built into windows ten so let me give you look at how that
works so over here I have...I should point out we need new hardware for this
and I don't have that hardware working today fact we're going to try demo of that a session on
thursday so you're seeing a simulation I'm going to do is connect my phone and.
Let's see you get this going.
Once I connect my phone I want you to think of this I've got a bluetooth keyboard a bluetooth
mouse and a screen just a screen that I'm connecting via html
I okay so because this phone software has all the core component tree that's
highly shared between the pc things like bluetooth keyboarding mice their supported and,
you might notice I'm not sure if the...shows this but at the top of my phone screen now it says
...for mouse and keyboard controller I could tap that then get essentially a mouse pad on
my phone but I don't need to do that because I have a full bluetooth mouse and
keyboard right here up here on the monitor you'll notice this looks very familiar I mean
...the same start menu with tiles I had my phone now displayed like a start
menu and I want to start running apps to give you a sense of how
well the phone experience transforms through continuum to give you a very
pc like experience...
launch powerpoint this is the version of powerpoint that comes with the phone and,
what you see on the big-screen here sure looks like the version of powerpoint that you would see
on a pc because in fact it is the same code as the version
of powerpoint that you would download from the store and see
on a pc I can do things like use my mouse and keyboard to create a new slide
...up here use the ribbon to insert pictures remember this
is my phone so as I am inserting the photos I bring up my photos this is the
calmer role of my phone and the...photos that I've synched from one drive
...choose...appropriate desert picture from a trip I made to utah and
I'll insert that into my powerpoint presentation
...completely natural and familiar way using the keyboard
...mouse let's look at some other examples...the click here to go into male
and the outlook mail client that comes with windows ten pc's
...comes with phone's is now viewed and it looks completely familiar here's my
mail folders I can choose a message in my inbox and
...click the reply button where I have the full our of the word engine
embedded righted outlook for doing replies and there's the familiar ribbon you can see here and,
is asking me to update the latest expense report eric's going to give me the
...expenses so I'm going to switch over here to excel where we're
doing arcs spence reporting and you'll see here's excel the
universal windows app excel running on the phone but looking the
same as it would on the pc I'll choose the my expense reporting app and look at
this my phone just buzz I got a text from...right there I'm going to
click to navigate on my phone screen separately to my text app
...hold to get the context manual choose copy because I'm going to copy
from that text right here to my a december sell
and of course my brain is wired to know the keyboard shortcuts for all these apps
...hit control v to...use my task switch...to come back to
the outlook email client and I can do a quick reply and sent?
Think about this with continuum for
phones we believe any screen can be your pc.
Imagine that your company has a touchdown space where anyone could
connect their tablet or their phone to keyboards mice and screens and
then use their apps with their data and the full our of a keyboard
and mouse or imagine you're on vacation and your hotel room can
become a theater or you connect your phone to the screen you let your kids watch a movie while you use
the second screen to catch up on your email imagine the effect this can have on
mobile first countries or individuals could be as productive with the phone that
they're buying if they can't buy a full pc so
what we're trying to show here today with continuum is our unique vision for
phones and enabling them to scale-up to a full pc like experience
and what we have so far is just the first step because it requires all of you
writing these universal windows apps whose you why can scale and it just
...different form factors input types and screen sizes as I said this
capability will require new devices that can drive dual screen and you'll hear more about
them later so that is my quick look at how we're going to help all of you and
are end-users discover value in the windows ecosystem on the
...screen on the start screen with core...with microsoft edge and how we're going to
...great new devices with continuum and I'm now
...the stage alex...man who's going to tell
you even more about some great new devices thanks-a-lot?
Thank you drill and good morning everyone now
...showed you how to do incredible things with windows from the
little screen to the big-screen now I
get the pleasure to show you how to do incredible things with windows on
...screens that all with the same familiar tools and
skills you already have it's so real being here today less than
one hundred days since the mix hologram with our world less than one
hundred days ago we showed you how windows holographic
amplifies what is human about each of us humans
living the real-world and we should not be confined to the virtual or just
that digital we experience
...in three-dimensions remove we see and we
hear in three-dimensions our dreams fantastic
all entropy url start in the real-world.
Windows holographic embraces this notion of experiencing
life in three-dimensions by mixing digital content writing
to your world writing to your life with more reality
than ever before now the truth of the mattress people not the
vices are mobile and we are ready for technology to
move beyond devices to move beyond screens and pixels and to move beyond
today's digital borders now in january we
showed you glamorous of this holographic landscape.
Go immerse of this more natural
way of interacting with digital content we introduce microsoft
holler lance the world's first and only fully untapped
Holographic computer and I have
to admit we have been humbled by the outpouring of enthusiasm
...from consumers to businesses and the response we received
from developers like yourselves has been remarkable
on behalf of the entire microsoft team thank you we
share your enthusiasm and today we take the next step in
an bailing the windows holographic platform focus on you
...the creators the windows
developers so let's get started by
take unique tour of windows holographic and to help us with that please
help me welcome stage one of the creative...behind hologram daring.
Now before we start let me explain to set up a little bit darrin is wearing out
hollow lengths and he sees this globe feb we
showed you january ride in his world.
Now we also have discussed them camera...over here so the you can see the hologram
up on the screens as if the camera is wearing a hollow lance now
when we introduced windows holographic the globe was just a
slide.
Today darrin is experiencing it
...universal windows app and guess what it's running on windows
To windows holographic.
This is life with hologram and as you can see
darrin has customized space.
Instead of digging through menus everything is right where he wants
Whether it's microsoft edge photos are video apps.
These are simply universal windows apps...place...hologram so whether it's a
...on the wall or something a little bit more dimensional like
my loyal companion fang here hey buddy you can customize
your space the way you want.
Now I want to add something to myspace so I'm going to pull up my holographic start menu.
I'm going to open up scape.
On the worst keeping in touch so I'm going to
take the people the matter most to me.
...them to this wall right here.
That way every time I walk into this room or see
...smiling faces and be inspired to reach out to them.
We all creatures of habit and we do different things in different spaces
in our homes this stage as an example is modeled after
their and apartment, yeah, and,
this is where I...out my apartment and surround myself with the applications that I want to access
or just check out for example.
And, planning a trip to hawaii and a couple weeks so I place this awesome whether
app over here so when I'm moving around I can easily glance
...reference it and understand what the weather's going to be like when I get there hopefully still hot.
Then if I look up here on the wall to my left I've got a video player
simply.
Reach out...tab ...the...
What...has...around the house?
Should be confine to watching just on one wall should be able to take
is entertainment with him anywhere in
remain hands-free as he does it, yeah, so, all I need to say is follow me?
Now wherever I go my house my entertainment tags along.
And,...gets where I'm going.
I simply place it and.
Get...as big as I want.
That's not something just a video player does every single universal windows app says
the same capabilities for example, I place...calendar over here because
...alex I'll tell you I'm late for pretty much every meeting so this makes it a guy like
me makes a lot easier for me to check in and see what I've got coming up next
...discoveringuses for hologram
...every day we know with all you hear build
...towards that we're going to be discovering new uses every second of inspiring time
...see out there thank you there and.
As you just saw holographic computing can
seamlessly.
Connected digital world with real-life this mix reality
...permission to read...productivity by creating experience
is not possible and any other device or any other platform
back in january we ask you to imagine an architect walking around or designs
while clients review them remotely now the construction industry is
a multi-billion-dollar industry yet many of their processes
...unchanged over the past few months we have had
the great honor to partner with an organization that has been transforming
the construction industry for over sixty years so let's take a sneak peek at
how holographic computing enabled by windows...is fundamentally
changing how they think about architecture construction and collaboration.
Architects are dealing with...and spaces inline ...agreements three-d and,
then you need to the...set of the...
Poland's presented completely paradigm attribute provides design solutions for architects
and structure engineers anything that involves getting dirty is our business
literally hundreds of enterprises can be represented on-the-job site.
...the best way those companies have...with each other
is paper drawings but people aren't good at visualizing three-d microsoft
head-mounted self-contained computer that lets you see...
Get a physical model is that as focus point for the team to
...around you get the hologram with the flexibility with
...two-run quick iteration...with broaden the...you
...you say that mounts go off the screen...to holographic space in your
...with the hologram...the thing that we can do for architect's
...really give them which higher confidence around decision-making why we could do that is we
...chilean this themselves and the same...building and
...street-side and other buildings but...moi.
Visualizing design data in the contents of...environment
...much better way to make sure...is...correctly.
Microsoft follow...allows you to collaborate with
somebody regardless of distance like they were there moi.
They're trying to the door there's have been by
...looking at this spain were interacting with
that about a problem that we can save and being able to solve that problem
with all the data that we need in front of us as.
...I'm talking...enterprise construction I
always compared to people trying to make music
together pre-trial semis contributed to the harmony...the...should be completely
...by greater says I've been doing this for a while as a lot of these new things coming
go moi.
Expect in five years we'll all be interacting with the world.
Follow
gramm's are already being sculpted by some of the most creative people around now
with this ability to design and...you have a new medium to express
...creativity to visualize are work
in share ideas your digital creations become so much more relevant when they
come to life in the real-world but that's just the beginning of what hologram
...windows holographic also provides deal with
a unique opportunity to change how you teach and learn more effective
weights.
On january twenty first...to imagine a surgeon learning a procedure without picking
up a scalpel.
Since then we have partner within institution a custom to thinking beyond
the possible and to show us what they have been up to please help me
welcome onstage professor mark...from case western reserve university in
rt member michelle hi mark layouts...more.
Cellmark is part of a team from case western in the cleveland
clinic we invited them to use windows holographic to advance medical
education beyond what is possible what today state of the art taken
away thanks alex today we use a combination of cadavers and
medical illustrations to teach students anatomy this is a curriculum and hasn't drastically changed over a
hundred years because...simply hasn't been another way?
...reality of the hollow...has the potential to
revolutionize this education by bringing three-d content into the real-world.
...biggest challenges for students learning anatomy is understanding the body
and three-dimensions and all the different systems fit together using
hologram as we can easily separate and focus
...individual systems.
For example,
we can focusing on the femur and students can immediately see some
of types of fractures they may one-day encountering the clinic.
I can leverage all of these new capabilities
while maintaining the important connection with my students were both wearing a hollow
...I can see what they're looking at what
they're interacting with I can assess their progress and they
communicate with me and each other naturally, for example,
I can see if...has a question in class whether gwen has a question while learning remotely.
cadaver doesn't move this makes it difficult to see the way living body actually works.
...doesn't have this limitation systems can be animated
easily see how things function.
Let's take a look at the center of the cardiovascular system the heart
amazing organ reality it's about the size of your fits.
Withhold...we can easily scale-up the hard...students you
...new details.
We can even see inside the hard to see the valves and action.
This is a new way of seeing...it has the potential
help students understand the structure and physiology of the body in a way that's just not possible
...what you've just seen is a vision of how...could enhance one single
...but as an educator it's easy for me
to see that it's not just anatomy the could benefit from this technology this could
...everyone learns.
Imagine for a moment some of the other fields...could be change.
For example, chemistry and genetics.
In paleontology.
And, the best part is we get to help to
...that future together I can't wait to see what you future holographic developers
...going to do with this amazing technology thanks thank you...thank you michelle.
And, thank you to our friends at case western
in the cleveland clinic from nasa gpl to trimble.
To case western these are just a few of the amazing partners we
are actively collaborating with transform different industries now...hologram
have become part of our everyday life.
Now I feel very fortunate to be in
this moment in time all the different pieces are starting to fall into place.
As we entered this decade the amount of processing our you can
get into a small form factor for a reasonable price point
is just staggering even in the last few years as we develop kuala
...the...optics sensors and
...has allowed us to move forward a
few orders of magnitude now people used to say computers today can
do enough my abstract just fine the internet...just fine
we going to do with all of this extra computing our
and the answer to that is that we're going to put a different emphasis on it you
workloads focus on solving brand you problems in other words we are
going to start using all of this our specifically to help us understand
humans in the world around us so...you do this.
With no wires.
With no markers
no external cameras with no phones
and no connection to a pc required...learn a little bit more
about this amazing magical device that is microsoft hollow lengths.
The hardware allows us to take these visions these ideas about these
new products and make it all real imagine a computer that allows you put
your images anywhere and you can interact with things as a combination of the real-world
and telegrams you have a bunch of different systems that need to come together in one big
symphony...easy-to-understand is...onion the sudden another layer things which you
submerged only have...figure that out now we don't have room for error we don't have room for
...you don't have room for those normal things that happen...working with these people across the
world...together and to...spry new product.
We envision...all-in-one device...built-in
batteries hands-free ...switching or the you have to come up with holographic
...because they're constantly producing data every single millisecond moi
...successful complex...you it's very simple
...pure it's to accommodate so many requirements
...if contents the audio components need to take in all of that information about...my
head...am I looking so that your brain knows that there's something real over there enclosure
...barometer users...break-away distribution...many sensors on
this product to read all those in real-time and to do that in a very powerful shun
...requires the our of what they develop with the new version of
windows we need to get the hardware just right so that we can sort of understand creativity in the world's.
I think we have great ideas...knowledge of developers
...hundreds are great ideas and that's what bill...outranked want to get out
to people show them hate israel and this actually works out
With windows stan kuala...are universal windows apps
...universal windows apps can be made to work on
windows holographic everything you have seen here today is a
universal windows app developers this opens up
...you've been of innovation any new vein of opportunity with hologram
...having you canvas to express
or creativity your apps can come to life and they can be experience
naturally in the world around you but seeing is believing so
let's take a look at how portability of experiences
enabled by windows ten can change the way
...like you interact with the physical things that you built
in to show us mixing hologram with io t please help
me welcome onstage my very good friend...
I'd like...may be fifteen this year millions of people we use maker
kids like this one to enter
robot competitions and learn about electronics many of them we use raspberry
pi to which now supports windows ten...core we were...to see
...we could do with the same hardware and hollow length so let me show you
the fifteen wake-up up.
...to the real be fifteen.
Because everyone knows...device has api
for human an environment understanding we were able to overlay
a holographic robot on top of a physical one and one thing we notice
all working as you need your data to be easily accessible but adding
...of this frame increases your cost and there's no way to see all that information at
once so let me show you how we check on our data...fifteen control panel.
This...you...system as a universal windows app.
I'm pulling the data from be fifteen making as big as I needed to be
and placing awards relevant in my...and I love it
...have to actually go back to her desk to do it this is a great example of how windows
stand mixer digital life more powerful by connecting it with
...real-life that's freight you
can waste a lot of time tweaking variables on another device before you test.
But, if all I need to do is something simple like
change lady color I can use a control scheme.
Like this.
So, that's how we envision controls and displays evolving
great hologram now so many industrial robots
...paths safely through their
...let's take a look at how me cco can help you
...navigate and how hologram can help so befitting
sensors aren't created detecting obstacles but the cool thing is they don't have to
be my hollow...can communicate that information...fifteen
finding mode now with windows holographic we can scan and environment we can
...up movement tasks and visualize the robots bath?
So, all I have to do is...chapter ground my hollow
...interprets the three-d points and tells be fifteen when to turn and
went to move forward now this is a great example of how portable
...experiences can be fifteen
...have to know its environment
the room understanding comes from windows holographic but
what happens when the environment actually changes that's no problem because
...I'm always aware...fifteen I can see it updated its route to
go around you and this is critical if you're working with bigger robots like those
and automotive manufacturing you need to always be aware of a robots intentions
...helps developers understand robots better at any scale or
...any scenario this is just amazing thank you so much
be curl and nice to be bfifty...fifteen say goodbye.
Simulator...moi.
Now at some point in time you get this feeling you could actually be creating
something meaningful but that feeling is materially different
from seeing architects excited about it from seen doctors in
...excited about it for seen developers like
you excited about it people outside of microsoft
...understanding the tools.
...understanding what they have in front of them who start painting with
ds brain you...and these brand-new...brushes.
Its humbling and...exciting at the same time.
It is in that spirit that we have brought hundreds of hollow
...devices.
Just like the ones you...today
...running on windows stand so that you hear
...can experience hologram...for yourselves over the next few days.
From holographic presentations featuring skylight.
To one-on-one demos like the trimble experience I showed you earlier
today.
And, my personal favorite are very own holographic
academy where you'll be able to build your very
first holographic experience from scratch we have all
...to share with you this week here at...now registration
for all of this begins after the keynote space is
limited so make sure you sign up for all of these activities by going
to the web or simply by using the build-up.
The holographic journey starts with you the windows developers
...right here and it starts right now and with that I want
to thank you and let's welcome...yeah, back when stage thank you.
Thank you alex that's just magical staff.
Hopefully you get the essence of our ambition with windows
when we say we want to move the users of windows to move from
meaning windows choosing windows to loving windows
at the core of our company is empowerment empowering us
...some mission to empower every
person in every organization on the planet to achieve more
and it starts by empowering every one of you every developer on the
planet thank you so very much for being here today and
but being at this conference I thought we will and today's
morning keynote by playing the music that david compose for us this
morning on staff bad thank you and have a great rest...thank you very much?
Samoa.